travelingmom.com 2008-10-02

# Traveling Mom - Privacy Policy

Travelingmom™ Privacy Policy

Travelingmom™ is designed to be a welcoming, safe site for you and your family to enjoy. We want you to feel secure sharing your personal information with us, and in return, we hope you will find the services offered by our site useful, timely, and relevant. We promise:

    * We will not rent or sell your personal information to any other party.  
    * We will notify you if we are going to use your personal information in a manner different from that stated at the time it is collected.  
    * You will have a choice as to whether or not we use your information in that different manner.  
    * If you ever want us to stop contacting you, just let us know and we will stop immediately after we have confirmed your decision.

If at any time you have concerns about how the personal information you have provided us is being used, please contact us at [webmaster@travelingmom.com.](mailto:webmaster@travelingmom.com.) If we do not provide you with an adequate response, let me know [korlando@travelingmom.com](mailto:korlando@travelingmom.com), and I will personally address your concerns and respond to you.

Our privacy policy contains the details of how travelingmom™ uses the information you provide. We value our customer and strive to provide quality service in every area. Thank you.

Warmest regards,

Kim Orlando  
Owner  
Travelingmom, LLC

Information Collection & Use

In general, you can visit this Web site without telling us who you are or revealing any information about yourself.

Log Files

Like most Web sites, our Web servers collect the domain names, not e-mail addresses, of visitors. This information is gathered automatically and stored in log files, and include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data.

We use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, to administer the site, to track users’ movements around the site, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole.

Age Policy.

This Web site is not intended for persons under 13 years of age. WE do not knowingly solict or collect personal information from or about children, and we do not knowingly market our products or services to children. If you are a parent or become aware of a child registered under the age of 13, please notify travelingmom™ at [webmaster@travelingmom.com](mailto:webmaster@travelingmom.com) or as provided at the end of this policy.

Note to Parents.

If your child is under 13 and has become a travelingmom™ member using a false age, please notify us as provided at the end of this policy and we will immediately close the account and nullify all personally identifiable information provided by them. If your child is under the age of 18 and you would like to know more about our site, information practices, stored information on your child, or how to close your child’s account, please contact us at [webmaster@travelingmom.com](mailto:webmaster@travelingmom.com) or as provided at the end of this policy.

Cookies

Our web servers collect the domain names, not the e-mail addresses, of visitors. Our web servers also seek (as many Web sites do) to place a "cookie" (a small data file) on your computer's hard drive which allows the server to determine the computer when it visits again, in order to track statistical information about navigation to and throughout certain areas of our site. This cookie is not used to obtain your name or any personal data, and the information that is tracked is used only for internal purposes, such as to improve site navigation and to measure the effectiveness of our promotional placements, and is not shared with anyone other than travelingmom affiliates and contractors who assist travelingmom in these efforts and are bound to confidentiality. However, if you prefer not to accept cookies, you can set your browser to reject them or to alert you before one is placed. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some areas of our site, such as contests or surveys, will be limited.

We use both session ID cookies and/or persistent cookies. We use session cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our site. A session ID cookie expires when you close you browser. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time. You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser's "help" file. [See http://support.microsoft.com/default.aspx?scid=kb;EN-US;278835 for more information about removing cookies from your computer.] We set a persistent cookie to store your passwords, so you don't have to enter it more than once. Persistent cookies also enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our site.

Some of our business partners (e.g., advertisers) use cookies on our site. We have no access to or control over these cookies. [See "Third Party Advertisers."] This privacy statement covers the use of cookies by travelingmom.com only and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers.

Registration

There are some portions of this Web site where you will be required to complete a registration form and/or create a username and password. During registration you are required to give contact information (such as name, address, telephone number, fax number, or e-mail address). We use this information to contact you about the services on our site in which you have expressed interest.

Travelingmom™ is the sole owner of information collected on travelingmom.com.

Orders

If you purchase a product or service from us, we request certain personally identifiable information from you on our order form. You must provide contact information (such as name, email, and shipping address) and financial information (such as credit card number, expiration date).

We use this information for billing purposes and to fill your orders. If we have trouble processing an order, we will use this information to contact you.

Surveys or Contests

From time-to-time we may provide you the opportunity to participate in contests or surveys on our site. If you participate, we will request certain personally identifiable information from you. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and you therefore have a choice whether or not to disclose this information. The requested information typically includes contact information (such as name and shipping address), and demographic information (such as zip code).

We use this information to notify contest winners and award prizes, to monitor site traffic or personalize the site (in the case of anonymous information collected in surveys), to send participants an e mail newsletter.

We may use a third party service provider to conduct these surveys or contests; that company will be prohibited from using our users' personally identifiable information for any other purpose. We will not share the personally identifiable information you provide through a contest or survey with other third parties unless we give you prior notice and choice.

Tell-A-Friend

If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about our site, we will ask you for your friend's name and email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site. Travelingmom™ stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email and tracking the success of our referral program.

Your friend may contact us at [webmaster@travelingmom.com](mailto:webmaster@travelingmom.com) to request that we remove this information from our database.

Communications from the Site

Special Offers and Updates. We will occasionally send you information on products, services, special deals, or promotions. You can sign up for these e-mails from us on our registration page.

Out of respect for your privacy, we present the option not to receive these types of communications. Please see the "Choice and Opt-out."

Newsletters. If you wish to subscribe to our newsletter(s), we will use your name and email address to send the newsletter to you. Out of respect for your privacy, we provide you a way to unsubscribe. Please see the "Choice and Opt-out" section.

Service-related Announcements. We will send you strictly service-related announcements on rare occasions when it is necessary to do so. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance, we might send you an email. You may opt-out of these communications. Please see "Choice and Opt-out."

Customer Service. Based upon the personally identifiable information you provide us, we will send you a welcoming email to verify your username and password. We will also communicate with you in response to your inquiries, to provide the services you request, and to manage your account.

Profile

We store information that we collect through cookies, log files, clear gifs, and/or third party sources to create a "profile" of your preferences in order to provide tailored promotions and marketing offers and to improve the content of the site for you.

We do not share your profile with other third parties.

Uses of Information

Domain name information that we collect is not used to personally identify you and instead is aggregated to measure the number of visits, average time spent on the site, pages viewed, etc. We use this information to measure the use of our site and to improve the content of our site.

When other information is collected from you, such as your name and e-mail address, we generally let you know at the time of collection how we will use the personal information. Usually, we use the personal information you provide only to respond to your inquiry or to process your request. This information may be shared with other businesses, but only if necessary to fulfill your request or for related purposes.

Third Party Advertisers

The ads appearing on this Web site are delivered to users by Google, our advertising partner. We share Web site usage information about users with a reputable third party Google for the purpose of targeting our Internet banner advertisements on this site.

Google uses cookies and other technologies on this site, which allow it to recognize a user's cookie when a user visits this site. The information that Google collects and shares through this technology is not personally identifiable.

For more information about our third-party advertiser, or to learn more about the choices available to you regarding this anonymous information, please click here.

Links to Other Sites

This Web site contains links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by travelingmom™, LLC. While we try to link only to sites that share our high standards and respect for privacy, please be aware that we, travelingmom™, LLC, are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites.

We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every Web site that collects personally identifiable information.

This privacy statement applies only to information collected by this Web site.

Information Sharing and Disclosure

Aggregate Information (non-personally identifiable). We share aggregated demographic information about our user base with our partners and advertisers. This information does not identify individual users.

We do not link aggregate user data with personally identifiable information.

Personally Identifiable Information. We DO NOT Share Personally Identifiable Information with Third Parties.

Legal Disclaimer

We reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our Web site

Choice/Opt-out

If you no longer wish to receive our newsletter and promotional communications, you may opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each newsletter or communication or by emailing us at [webmaster@travelingmom.com](mailto:webmaster@travelingmom.com), or you may contact us at 51 Orchard Place, Greenwich, CT 06830 to opt-out.

You will be notified when your personal information is collected by any third party that is not our agent or service provider, so you can make an informed choice as to whether or not to share your information with that party.

Bulletin Boards/Forums/Chat Rooms

If you use a bulletin board or chat room on this site, you should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of these forums, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in these forums.

Access to Personally Identifiable Information

If your personally identifiable information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct, update, delete or deactivate it by or by emailing our Customer Support at [webmaster@travelingmom.com](mailto:webmaster@travelingmom.com) or by contacting us by telephone or postal mail at the contact information listed below.

Security of Collected Information

The security of your personal information is important to us. We maintain strict physical, electronic, and administrative safeguards to protect your personal information from unauthorized or inappropriate access.

We restrict access to information about you to those Travelingmom employees who need to know the information to respond to your inquiry or request. Employees who misuse personal information are subject to disciplinary action.

We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can send email us at [webmaster@travelingmom.com.](mailto:webmaster@travelingmom.com.)

Business Transitions

In the event travelingmom™, LLC goes through a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, your personally identifiable information will likely be among the assets transferred. You will be notified via prominent notice on our Web site for 30 days prior to any such change in ownership or control of your personal information.

Changes in this Privacy Statement

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the homepage, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it.

We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by e-mail, or by means of a notice on our home page.

Contact Us

If you have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy, please contact us at: [webmaster@travelingmom.com.](mailto:webmaster@travelingmom.com.)

or

Travelingmom™, LLC  
51 Orchard Place  
Greenwich, CT 06830

We welcome your questions and suggestions about our privacy policy. 

Trackback(0)

Comments 

Write comment
